Personal Summary

Software Developer with 4 years of experience working with complex web and mobile solutions for various companies and clients. I am currently working as a Front-end Software Engineer, working in both web and mobile and periodically on AdonisJS back-end Node framework.

Core Skills

- Proficiency in Javascript/Typescript development
- Software testing knowledge.
- Great experience in Javascript Frameworks:
 - React
 - React Native
 - NextJS
 - Vite
 - Ехро
 - Adonis JS
- Strong problem solving skills.
- Excellence in **verbal** and **written** communication
- Conflict resolution knowledge

Contact

Address: Travessa Dom Amando, n° 984, NBH Santa Clara, Santarém - PA, Brazil

E-mail:

joaopauloalencarrodriguesagmail.com

Github: github.com/joaorodrs

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/joaorodrs

Certifications

IGNITE REACT

Rocketseat Education - 2023

IGNITE REACT NATIVE

Rocketseat Education - 2022

USER CENTERED DESIGN

PUCRS - 2024

Languages

- English (Fluent)
- Portuguese (Native)

João Rodrigues

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Work Experience

FULLSTACK ENGINEER

Eu Fit Brasil (freelance) / April 2020 - January 2021

FRONT-END ENGINEER

Inovan.do / March 2021 - present

- React Native mobile app for Android and IOS
- NodeJS API server
- App deployment in AppStore and Google Play Store, and API deploy into Digital Ocean
- Dashboard admin pages creation and maintenance
- Complex solutions using geolocalization API's and maps for specific projects
- 'Bullet proofed' basic implementations (2FA, sessions, socket.io, lists, profile permissioning)
- Worked on projects documentation
- Improved the performance of many software implementations significally.
- Actively participated in planning meetings and suggested many feature changes before and during the projects executions.

Education

UNAMA -AMAZON UNIVERSITY

BSc. Business | March 2021 - 2024

- Business adminstration
- Leadership and team management
- Organization, systems and methods
- Performance indicators

INSTITUTO FEDERAL DO PARÁ

High School | January 2018 - December 2020